Finding Aid for University of Michigan Center for Chinese Studies Records 1958-2010
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Directors Correspondence, 1972-1982
  The Director's Correspondence (.25 linear feet) series consists of incoming and outgoing correspondence from 1972 to 1982 during the period in which Albert Feuerwerker was the official director of the center and both Rhodes Murphey and Allen Whiting spent time as acting director. It is arranged alphabetically, although the researcher should be aware that documents may be filed by name of correspondent, name of organization, or subject heading. The correspondence illustrates the importance of the CCS director's role in the larger national and international scholarly communities of sinologists. Topics addressed in the correspondence include research, conferences, projects, and the formation and review of other Chinese studies departments. Of special interest is the correspondence found in the 'A' and 'R' folders that documents the response of China scholars in the West to the incarceration of Soviet sinologist Vitali Rubin.
  - A-W, 19 folders (Box 3)
- Asia Library, 1962-1982
  The Asia Library series (.25 linear feet) contains materials from 1962 to 1982 consisting of annual reports, budgetary records, proposals, and correspondence. The library, part of the university's Divisional Libraries, was established in 1948 and has grown to become one of the largest and most prestigious research libraries of its type in the country. It is administered jointly by the university's various area centers.
  - Annual Reports, 1972-1980 (Box 3)
  - Conference, 1974 (Box 3)
  - Funds/Budgets, 1967-1980 (Box 3)
  - General Files
    - 1962-1979, 2 folders (Box 3)
    - 1981-1982 (Box 3)
  - Library of Congress, 1968 (Box 3)
  - Proposal for Institute on East Asian Librarianship, 1979 (Box 3)
  - Accession, 1997 (Box 3)
- Michel Oksenberg
  In 1997, records identified as belonging to the CCS record were transferred out of the Michel Oksenberg collection. These were largely files of director Alexander Eckstein and related to the East Asian Studies Capital Campaign and to the grant proposals written by CCS to various foundations. These files are located in the Michel Oksenberg series.
  - Association for Comparative Economic Studies Journal (Box 3)
  - China Institute in America (Box 3)
  - Chinese medical study (plans and proposals), 1974 (Box 3)
  - Conferences (CCS & U-M School of Public Health) (Box 3)
  - Corner House office miscellanea (Box 3)
  - East Asian Studies Capital Campaign, 1974-1977; 4 folders (Box 3)
  - East Asian Studies Capital Campaign, 1974-1977; 1 folders (Box 4)
  - Grant proposals and related materials
    - American Council of Learned Societies (Chinese economic studies), 1975-1977 (Box 4)
    - Arms Control and Disarmament Agency, 1966-1971 (Box 4)
    - Mellon Foundation, 3 folders (Box 4)
    - National Science Foundation, 4 folders (Box 4)
    - Sloan Foundation, 1972-1973 (Box 4)
    - Social Science Research Council, 1972-1973 (Box 4)
  - University of Michigan Board of Regents trip to the People's Republic of China (1974-1976) (Box 4)